Guide to the United States Labor Education in the Americas Project (L.E.A.P) records, "1983-2013 LAC0016
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
United States Labor Education in the Americas Project (L.E.A.P) Records
1983-2013
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
United States Labor Education in the Americas Project
LAC0016
124.5 Linear Feet
This collection houses the correspondence and office records of Executive Director Stephen Coats and other staffers from the United States Labor Education in the Americas Project (USLEAP). It's mission was promoting full respect for labor rights globally, and securing economic justice for workers in Latin America and the Caribbeann. Materials included are Stephen Coats' conference and research notes, drafts of various USLEAP newsletters and reports, assorted activist literature, newspaper clippings, and both internal and official communications, the bulk of which are printed emails. Materials are dated from 1983 to 2013.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into 8 series: Labor Organizing and Trade, Fair Trade, Newsletters, Maquiladora/Sweatshop Campaigns, Board Materials, U.S. Media, Stephen Coats Papers, and Audio, Digital, and Video Recordings. Materials within each series are organized chronologically by year.
Biographical / Historical
Executive Director Stephen Coats was born in northern Thailand in 1952. His parents, the Reverend Robert and Patricia Coats, were Baptist missionaries that ministered small, remote villages inhabited by the ethnic Karen group straddling the northern Burma/Myanmar border. Growing up in these communities, Stephen Coats would remain an active church member and supporter of present-day religious missions serving Karen refugees.
After moving to the United States to finish his senior year in high school, Stephen Coats pursued undergraduate studies at New College in Sarasota, Florida. He then studied theology at Yale Divinity School under Rev. William Sloane Coffin, and obtained his divinity degree and Master's Degree in Economics at Union Theological Seminary in New York City. Consequently, Coats sought a career with Bread for the World, an anti-poverty group focusing on ending global hunger and disease through a Christian citizen's movement. As the organization's policy director, Coats worked on global and domestic food aid, labor standards in trade pacts, and expansions of Earned Income Tax Credit. Here he also met his wife of 31 years, Kim Bobo (founder and Executive Director of the Interfaith Worker Justice group)and the couple would later move to Chicago in 1987.
In 1990, Stephen Coats became Executive Director U.S./Guatemala Labor Education Project (USGLEP), as it was then-known, and moved its main office to Chicago. The organization had been founded three years earlier within the New York City headquarters of the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU), through the efforts of Dave Dyson, ACTWU Union Label Director. Within its first ten years, USGLEP campaigned against poor working conditions and labor code violations in the coffee and apparel manufacturing (or "maquiladora") export sectors solely in Guatemala. By 1998, the organization changed its name to USLEAP to reflect its expanded mission to support labor organizing in banana, coffee, and flower commodity export sectors throughout the Western Hemisphere.
A key principle of USLEAP under Stephen Coats was building horizontal relationships with Latin American workers organizations, serving as a "go-to group" for coordinating among various labor, religious, and non-governmental groups while defering to the interests of their allies. In the United States, Coats and other USLEAP staffers organized campaigns for negotiating corporate codes of conduct for companies like Chiquita, Starbucks, and other U.S. firms expanding in Latin America. USLEAP staff members lobbied Members of Congress and their staffers through grass roots action alerts, workshops, and press conferences on impunity and inadequate labor protections in U.S. trade agreements. USLEAP also communicated with the Department of Labor and Office of the U.S. Trade Representative by filing charges for labor rights infringment under U.S. law. While not considering itself a research organization, USLEAP also produced briefing materials, reports, and econometric trade data to keep Latin American unions informed on policy debates within the United States. Finally, Coats sought to combat impunity by giving financial support and protection to trade union leaders targeted by death threats and attempted assassinations in Mexico, Honduras, Guatemala, and Colombia.
On April 2, 2013, Stephen Coats passed away from a heart attack at the age of 61. He is survived by Kim, his twin sons Eric and Benjamin Coats, and his siblings Margaret Spors, Mark Coats, John Coats and Scott Coats.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection houses the correspondence and office records of Executive Director Stephen Coats and other staffers from the United States Labor Education in the Americas Project (USLEAP). It's mission was promoting full respect for labor rights globally, and securing economic justice for workers in Latin America and the Caribbeann. Materials included are Stephen Coats' conference and research notes, drafts of various USLEAP newsletters and reports, assorted activist literature, newspaper clippings, and both internal and official communications, the bulk of which are printed emails. Materials are dated from 1983 to 2013.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the United States Labor Education in the Americas, 2014 [2014.014].
Labor unions; Labor; Education
- Labor Organizing and Trade, 1987-2013; Series 1
  Arrangement
  This series is organized into 7 subseries: El Salvador, Honduras, and Nicaragua, AFTA- Ecuador, Peru, and Bolivia, NAFTA & Mexico, CAFTA & Caribbean Basin Initiative, Colombia, Guatemala, and Venezuela.
  Materials in this series are organized chronologically by year. Folder titles within each box are arranged alphabetically. Folders with similiar titles or themes are marked by numbers in brackets to indicate their order.
  - El Salvador, Honduras, and Nicaragua, 1987-2012; Series 1 Subseries 1
    Scope and Contents
    This series houses research notes and correspondence of Steve Coats and other USLEAP staffers on labor strikes, union organizing campaigns, and commodity-based trade data for El Salvador, Honduras, and Nicaragua. The bulk of materials consists of printed email correspondence and attached news articles; other materials include assorted document drafts, handwritten notes, conference handouts/mailings, and newspaper clippings on disputes on labor organizing and trade policy with each particular country.
    For direct correspondence by Steve Coats with a specific individual, see Series 7-"Steve Coats Papers."
    For materials dealing with other Central American countries, or focusing on the Central American Free Trade Agreement, see Series 1, Subseries 4.
    For materials focusing on events or policy for a specific business or commodity, see Series 2-"Fair Trade."
    For materials focusing on a specific 'maquila' or sweatshop-related dispute, see Series 4-"Maquiladora/Sweatshop Campaigns."
    Materials are organized chronologically by year. Folder titles within each box are arranged alphabetically. Folders with similiar titles are marked by numbers in brackets to indicate their order, returning the date of the first folder.
    Materials focusing on El Salvador from 1989 to 2011 are housed in Boxes 56 to 59; materials focusing on Honduras from 1997 to 2012 are housed in Boxes 61 to 64; finally, materials focusing on Nicaragua from 1996 to 2007 are housed in Boxes 65 to 69. At the end of materials for each particular country, the chronological cycle returns to the earliest listed date.
    - El Salvador campaigns, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Oversize 135, Folder 1)
    - National Labor Committee, El Salvador, 1989-1991; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - National Labor Commitee, 1996-1998; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Oversize 135, Folder 3)
    - El Salvador-Independent Monitoring, 1997-1998; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - El Salvador-Pesquera, Crystal Cave, 1997-1998; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - El Salvador-Pesquera, Industrial, 1997-1998; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - El Salvador-Pesquera, San Marino Exports, 1998; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - El Salvador-STITSCPA, 1997-1998; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - El Salvador-DoAll [1], 1999-2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - El Salvador-DoAll plan [2], 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - El Salvador-DoAll [3], 2001-2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - El Salvador-Gap, Inc., 1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - El Salvador-Adidas, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - El Salvador-SUTTEL union, 2000-2001; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - Tainan Enterprises, El Salvador [1], 2001; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 56, Folder 13)
    - Tainan Enterprises, El Salvador [2], 2003; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 56, Folder 14)
    - Tainan Enterprises, El Salvador [3], 2003; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 56, Folder 15)
    - Tainan-Gene Palumbo, 2001; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 56, Folder 17)
    - El-Salvador-Tainan Enterprises research, 2001-2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 56, Folder 17)
    - El Salvador-Tainan Enterprises, 2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 56, Folder 18)
    - El Salvador-Tainan Enterprises agreement, 2002; Series 1 Series 1 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - El-Salvador-Tainan Enterprises meetings, 2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Independent Monitoring Group of El Salvador, 2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Tainan Enterprises/AFL-CIO, 2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Tainan clients, 2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Tainan Enterprises, El Salvador closing, 2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Tainan Enterprises, February-May email, 2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Tainan Enterprises, May-June email, 2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Tainan Enterprises, July-September email, 2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - Tainan Enterprises, October-December email, 2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - Tainan Enterprises, El Salvador-research, 2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 57, Folder 11)
    - Tainan Enterprises/Gap. inc, El Salvador, 2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - Tainan Enterprises-Jeff Hermanson, 2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Tainan Enterprises/The Limited, 2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Tainan Enterprises negotiations/preparation, 2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Tainan Enterprises negotiations, 2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Tainan Enterprises-Piers Imports, 2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Tainan Enterprises/USLEAP direct correspondence, 2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Tainan Enterprises/UNITE, 2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - El Salvador-Just Garments [1], 2003; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - El Salvador-Just Garments [2], 2004; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - El Salvador-1199 SEIU Delegation report, 2003; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - El Salvador-Tainan/Gap, Inc. [1], 2003-2004; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - El Salvador-Gap and Leader Garments [2], 2003; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - El Salvador-Healthcare, 2003; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - El Salvador-Land's End [1], 2003; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Worker Rights Consortium-El Salvador, Primo and Land's End [2], 2003; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - El Salvador-Lido, 2003; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - El Salvador-Satellite investigation, 2003; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - El Salvador-Makalot/RooHsing, 2004; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - El Salvador-Just Garments manufacturing assessment, 2004; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 58, Folder 10)
    - El Salvador-Just Garments/No Sweat Apparel, 2004; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 58, Folder 11)
    - El Salvador-Just Garments [1], 2005; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 58, Folder 12)
    - El Salvador-Just Garments [2], 2006-2007; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 58, Folder 13)
    - El Salvador-Del Rio, 2006; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - El Salvador-Hermosa Manufacturing, 2006-2007; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - El Salvador-Quality/Elder Manufacturing, 2006-2007; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 59, Folder 12)
    - El Salvador-Just Garments closing, 2007; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 58, Folder 14)
    - El Salvador-Grupo Calvo, 2007; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 59, Folder 13)
    - El Salvador-Just Garments, 2008; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 58, Folder 15)
    - Peace Work-Change Comes to El Salvador, 2009; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 59, Folder 14)
    - El Salvador Labor Violence, 2010; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 59, Folder 15)
    - The Labor Movement: Who's Winning So Far? by Elaine Freedman, 2010; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 59, Folder 16)
    - Stop Union Busting in El Salvador, 2011; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 59, Folder 17)
    - Honduras campaigns, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Oversize 135, Folder 2)
    - Honduras Labor Movement, 1994-2004; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Honduras-Kimi/ByDesign, L.L.C., 1997-1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Honduras-Kimi Letters and updates [1], 1997-1998; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Honduras-Kimi Letters and updates [2], 1997-1998; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Honduras-Buena Vista, 1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Honduras-Cheil, 1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Honduras-Cheil, Gap. Inc., 1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Honduras-Continental Park, Dong Woo, 1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Honduras-Continental Park, Mi Kwang, 1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Honduras-Continental/Yoo Yang, 1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Honduras Embassy Request, West Chester, 1999-2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Honduras-Kimi, 1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Honduras-Kimi actions/alerts, 1999-2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Kimi/American Eagle Outfitters, 1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Honduras/Kimi and Archdiocesan Committee, 1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Honduras-Kimi closing letter, 1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - Honduras-Kimi/Dayton-Hudson Corporation, 1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - Honduras-Kimi/Gap, inc., 1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - Honduras-Kimi/Gear for Sports, 1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 60, Folder 11)
    - Honduras/Guantes Surenos, 1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 60, Folder 12)
    - Honduras-Kimi/JC Penny, 1999-2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 60, Folder 13)
    - Honduras-Kimi/Kohl's Department Stores, Inc., 1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 60, Folder 14)
    - Honduras-Kimi labels, 1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 60, Folder 15)
    - Honduras-Kimi Philips-Van Heusen, 1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 60, Folder 16)
    - Honduras-Kimi-Port Import Export Reporting Service (PIERS), 1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 60, Folder 17)
    - Honduras-Kimi/Rosenthal research, 1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 60, Folder 18)
    - Honduras-Kimi/Sears, 1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 60, Folder 20)
    - Honduras-Kimi updates, 1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 60, Folder 21)
    - Honduras-maquila/U.S. embassy, 1999-2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - Honduras-Yoo Yang information, 1999-2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Honduras-Yoo Yang/ITGLWF, 1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Honduras-Yoo Yang petition, 1999-2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Honduras-Yoo Yang/Phillips-Van Heusen, 1999-2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Honduras-Yoo Yang/STITCH, 1999-2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Honduras-Yoo Yang workers' interviews, 1999-2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - JanSport, 1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Kimi-labels/Continental Park, 1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 60, Folder 22)
    - Kimi meetings and updates, 1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 60, Folder 23)
    - Kimi-official correspondence, 1999-2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 60, Folder 24)
    - Kimi/USLEAP correspondence, 1999-2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 60, Folder 25)
    - UNITE/Honduras Memorandum of Understanding, 1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 60, Folder 26)
    - US Embassy in Honduras/Kimi, 1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Maquiladora Association of Honduras, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - Honduras and Guatemala sweatshops, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 11)
    - Honduras-Bodek and Rhodes research, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 12)
    - Honduras delegation, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 13)
    - Honduran Industrial Union, Puerto Corts, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Honduras-Kimi, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - Honduras-Kimi advertisement, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - Honduras-Kimi/Agabang USA, Inc., 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - Honduras-Kimi/Bodek and Rhodes research, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - Honduras-Kimi closing [1], 2000-2001; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 12)
    - Honduras-Kimi closing [2], 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 13)
    - Honduras-Kimi closing research, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 14)
    - Honduras-Kimi fact sheet, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 15)
    - Honduras-Kimi Gui Bang, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 16)
    - Honduras- Kimi information, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 17)
    - Honduras-Kimi, King Louie International, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 18)
    - Honduras-King Louie International, Bodek & Rhodes-Kimi [1], 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 19)
    - King Louie International import details [2], 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 20)
    - Honduras-Kimi/La Strada Fashions, Inc., 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 21)
    - Honduras-Kimi, letters of support/protest, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 22)
    - Honduras-Kimi, Modas Cielo, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 23)
    - Honduras-Kimi, move and potential close, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 24)
    - Honduras-Kimi/Potential/Periscope Sportswear Inc., 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 25)
    - Honduras-Kimi/KHIS [1/2], 2000-2001; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 26)
    - Honduras-KHIS research requests [2/2], 2000-2001; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 26)
    - Honduras-Kimi, USAS meeting with Bodek and Rhodes, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 28)
    - Honduras-Kimi/William Carter Company, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 29)
    - Honduran Embassy-Kimi, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 30)
    - Honduras-M Fine & Sons Manufacturing, web research, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 17)
    - Honduras-Manufacturero Cortes, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 14)
    - Honduras maquilas-Don Weiner correspondence, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 16)
    - Honduras maquilas-Scott Littlehale Correspondence, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 15)
    - Honduras-Nike/USAS, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 18)
    - Honduras research, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 19)
    - Honduras-SITTRANSPACIFIC, 2000-2001; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 20)
    - Honduras-SITTRANSPACIFIC, JC Penny, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 21)
    - Honduras/US Embassy, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 22)
    - Honduras-Harwood Companies, Inc. [1], 2001; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 23)
    - Honduras-Harwood Companies/Sara Lee [2], 2001; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 24)
    - Honduras-Sara Lee [3], 2001; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 25)
    - Honduras-Macor research, 2001; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 26)
    - Honduran maquilas, 2001; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 27)
    - Honduras-Samwood, 2001; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 28)
    - Honduras-SITRAMACOR [1], 2001; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 29)
    - Honduras-Sitramacor [2], 2001; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 30)
    - Honduras-Kimi, USAS meeting with Bodek & Rhodes, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 18)
    - Honduras-Yoo Yang, 2000-2001; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Honduras-Yoo Yang campaign, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Honduras-Yoo Yang campaign updates, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Honduras-Yoo Yang Company information, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Honduras-Yoo Yang exports, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - Honduras-Yoo Yang/Labor Ministry, 2000-2001; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - Honduras-Yoo Yang maquila packet, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 63, Folder 10)
    - Honduras-Yoo Yang and Phillips-Van Heusen/Human Rights Watch, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 63, Folder 11)
    - Honduras-Yoo Yang research notes, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 63, Folder 12)
    - Honduras Yoo Yang strategy and history, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 63, Folder 13)
    - Honduras-Yoo Yang/ SITRAIMASH [1], 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 63, Folder 14)
    - Yoo Yang/ SITRAIMASH agreement [2], 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 63, Folder 15)
    - Honduras-Yoo Yang/USLEAP direct correspondence, 2000-2004; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 63, Folder 16)
    - Honduras-Yoo Yang worker interviews, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 63, Folder 17)
    - Honduras-Yoo Yang Working Group, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 63, Folder 18)
    - Yoo Yang-Guess, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 63, Folder 19)
    - Yop Yang labels, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 63, Folder 20)
    - Yoo Yang-Preswick and Moore, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 63, Folder 21)
    - Kimi research, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 31)
    - Korea-Kimi Trading Company export details, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 32)
    - Korea Kimi Trading Company import details, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 62, Folder 33)
    - Behind the Label-Yoo Yang, 2001-2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 63, Folder 22)
    - Honduras-Yoo Yang, 2001; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 63, Folder 24)
    - Honduras-Yoo Yang campaign/negotiations, 2001; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 31)
    - Honduras-Yoo Yang "next steps", 2001-2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 32)
    - Honduras-Yoo Yang post-agreement, 2001-2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 61, Folder 33)
    - Honduras-Empresa Corazn [1], 2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Honduras- Corazn update [2], 2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Honduras-Empresa Corazn [3], 2002-2005; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Honduras-Empresa Corazn/Labor Ministry, 2003; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Honduras targeting and research, 2003-2005; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 64, Folder 5)